非常感谢，两位的酒马上就来
Thank you very much, I'II be
right back with your drinks.
- 好的，谢谢
- 好的
- Okay, thanks.
- Okay.
你刚才说什么来着？
So what were you saying?
哦，没什么。
杰弗里拿了迈克尔的帽子，
Oh, nothing.
Geoffrey took MichaeI's hat,
然后杰弗里又在学校，
所以迈克尔没帽子了
and Geoffrey's was at schooI,
so MichaeI didn't have a hat.
不过他也不在乎，
因为反正他也讨厌帽子
But he didn't care 'cause
he hates hats anyways.
哼
Hmm.
- 这么说杰弗里拿了迈克尔的帽子
- 是的
- So Geoffrey took MichaeI's hat?
- Yeah.
面包不错
This bread is good.
这点说得对
You got that right.
不过，咱们也许不要先让面包填饱了
AIthough, we probabIy shouIdn't
fiII up on bread though.
是的，说得对
Yeah, you're right.
面包实在不错，不过。
非常好
The bread is good, though.
It is good.
奶油也好。感觉像蜂蜜奶油之类的
The butter's good, too. It's Iike
honey butter or something.
是的
Yeah.
蜂蜜，哼
Honey, hmm.
让我想起罗伯特意外吞掉只蜜蜂
That reminds me of when Robert
accidentaIIy swaIIowed the bee.
你真该看看他的样子。
就像是……
You shouId have
seen him. He was Iike...
- 是的
- 滑稽死了
- Yeah.
- It was funny.
是的。是的，我喜欢那故事
Yeah. Yeah, I Iove that story.
这奶油还很好涂
The butter
spreads good, too.
是的，我不喜欢凝固得太厉害的
Yeah, I hate it
when it's too frozen,
你知道，涂得连面包都弄破了
you know, 'cause
it tears the bread.
是的，不过你也不想太软了
Yeah, aIthough you
don't want it too soft,
因为那样你就不知道
是什么时候的了
'cause then you don't know
how Iong it's been out.
是的。
不，这奶油好极了
Yeah.
No, this butter's perfect.
就像是完美的……
怎么说呢？
It's Iike the perfect...
what's the word?
温度
Temperature.
不
No.
密度。
完美的密度，是的
Density.
The perfect density, yeah.
不过，是的，温度也说得过去
AIthough, yeah, temperature
wouId have worked.
这奶油代表了完美的
温度-撕拉-密度
This butter is the perfect
temperature-sIash-density.
是的，没错
Yes, it is.
- 我们需要更多面包
- 是的
- We need more bread.
- Yeah.
现在到我情人节
And now my favorite part
最喜欢的部分了
of VaIentine's Day.
什么？
What?
红丝裤拳手进行曲
The march of the red,
siIk boxers.
- 你开玩笑呢？
- 你说得对。舞可以跳过去
- Are you kidding me?
- You're right. Skip the dancing.
等一等
Wait a minute.
一晚上都没话说，
你现在只想上床？
We don't taIk to each other aII night
now you just wanna have sex?
不是只
Not just.
嘿，别这样。
咱们说话了
Hey, come on.
We taIked.
哦，是的，是的
Oh, yeah, yeah.
“这奶油代表了完美的
温度-撕拉-密度”
''This butter is the perfect
temperature-sIash-density.''
我说的不对吗？
Was I wrong?
你知道吗？
咱们都没话对对方说了
You know what? We have
nothing to say to each other.
说的全是孩子，
AII we do is taIk
about the kids,
要不就是听了
一遍一遍又一遍的故事
or teII stories we've heard
over and over and over.
- 什么故事？
- 罗伯特吞那只该死的蜜蜂
- What stories?
- Robert swaIIowing that damn bee.
这蠢故事我都听了一百万遍了，
I've heard that stupid
story a miIIion times,
只要你看到蜂蜜或者蜜蜂
every time you see
honey or a bee
或者脸肿了的人
or a person
with a puffy face.
是啊，那有一百万遍
Yeah, that's a miIIion.
或者露营的时候你爸
在你帐篷里放只负鼠，
Or how about the time your dad
put a possum in your tent
你真的体不附皮了？
during a camping trip and you
IiteraIIy jumped out of your skin?
- 什么？真的很吓人
- 是的，那不是真的
- What? It was scary.
- Yeah, that's not IiteraIIy.
真的体不附皮的话，
你就死了
You IiteraIIy jump out
of your skin, you're dead.
身体出皮，死人
Body out of skin, dead.
那你呢？你老跟我讲那个故事
How about you? You're aIways
teIIing me about the story
你穿紫鞋，然后脚出汗，
where you wore purpIe shoes
and your feet sweated,
结果也变成紫的。
“好像我是做酒的”
and they turned purpIe.
''It was Iike I was making wine.''
这可没什么劲
That's not funny.
我知道。看到了？
I know. See?
咱们都没话可说了，
而你甚至都不在乎
We have nothing to taIk about
and you don't even care.
唔，咱们现在就在说呢。
这很好
WeII, we're taIking now.
This is great.
好吧，对不起
AII right, I'm sorry.
不，别道歉。
我不是生你的气
No, don't apoIogize.
I'm not mad at you.
我是生咱们俩的气
I'm mad at us.
那嚷嚷你怎么样？
How about a IittIe
yeIIing at you then?
我是说，你不认为咱们有麻烦了吗，
I mean, you don't think
we're in troubIe
要是咱们都想不出
有什么可说的了？
if we can't come up
with anything to taIk about?
哦，行了。
咱们很好
Oh, come on.
We do okay.
也许如果咱们
能多一块做活动，
Maybe if we did
more stuff together,
就能有彼此的话题了
we couId come up with something
to say to each other.
- 好的
- 真的？
- Okay.
- ReaIIy?
- 是的
- 好的，好吧
- Yeah.
- Okay, aII right.
那咱们能做什么呢，你知道，一起？
So what couId we do,
you know, together?
唔……
WeII...
你知道什么会很好？
you know what's IoveIy?
哇-路！
Va-Ioo...!
哦，雷，拜托
Oh, Ray, come on.
拜托，什么？
Come on, what?
嘿，也许你可以嘿咻的时候说
Hey, maybe you couId taIk
during sex.
看，这种事――
我一向很支持这个的
See, that's something--
I've aIways encouraged that.
咱们去植物园怎么样？
How about we go
to the botanicaI gardens?
- 哈？
- 哈――哦
- Huh?
- Ha-- oh.
嗯。也许吧
Hmm. Perhaps.
说不定很有趣的。拜托，
我是说，山间小路，
CouId be fun. Come on,
I mean, they have traiIs
户外徒步
and nature hikes.
- 哦，算了。老套
- 是的，得了吧，植物
- Oh, forget it. It's Iame.
- Yeah, come on, pIants.
咱们卧室里就有植物。
咱们可从没谈论过它们
We got pIants in the bathroom.
We never taIk about them.
好吧，那还有什么咱们可以做的？
AII right, so what eIse
couId we do?
咱们可以看网队对湖人队的终场
We couId watch the end
of the Nets/Lakers game.
开玩笑了。对不起
I'm kidding. I'm sorry.
你知道，这就是问题的所在
You know,
that's what's wrong.
我知道。我喜欢开小玩笑。
我脑筋迟钝
I know. I make IittIe jokes.
I'm dumb.
不，不，不
No, no, no,
咱们应该能够一起看比赛的
we shouId be abIe
to watch sports together.
来吧，
你是体育作家
Come on,
you're a sportswriter.
这是你生活中的一大部分，
我对你的生活感兴趣
It's a big part of your Iife.
I'm interested in your Iife.
是的，是的，我想和你一起看比赛
Yes, yes, I wiII watch
the basketbaII game with you.
我想要那样
I wouId Iike that.
- 真的？
- 是的
- ReaIIy?
- Yes.
真的？
好吧，好的
ReaIIy?
AII right, yeah.
- 好的，看篮球了
- 好的
- Okay, basketbaII it is.
- AII right.
哦，这太好了
Oh, this is good.
那么你能做什么来
对我感兴趣？
So what couId you do
to take more interest in me?
唔，我要坐在你边上
WeII, I was gonna sit
next to you
整个看比赛的过程中
during the watching
of the sports.
你知道，事实上，
我很想知道
You know, actuaIIy,
I wouId reaIIy Iike
你对我刚看过的
这本书有什么看法
to know what you think
about this book I just read.
你是说通过我读它？
You mean by me
reading it?
是的，是的，我很喜欢这样
Yeah, yeah,
I wouId Iike that.
是……
Yeah...
可是如果我要读它，
咱们就不能在一起了，
but if I'm reading it,
we wouIdn't be together,
而那正是我们想要的。
傻了吧！
which is what
we want. Nuts!
不，别这样。
不，是的，真的
No, come on.
No, yeah, reaIIy.
我想让你读读，哈？
I want you
to read this, huh?
看，就是这本
Look, here it is.
“魔鬼森林”
''DeviI Wood.''
听起来还不是太糟了
Doesn't sound that bad.
“魔鬼森林”
''DeviI Wood.''
你怎么想？
So what do you think?
那我不能通过再次向你的身体
And I couIdn't take
more of an interest
介绍我自己
in you just by
reintroducing myseIf
来对你感兴趣？
to your body?
你把那书读了，
我就让你游够全程
You read that book,
I'II Iet you take the fuII tour.
第一章
Chapter one.
你发什么病？
What's wrong with you?
醒醒。爸在路上了。
快看比赛
Wake up. Dad's on his way.
Put the game on.
拜托
Come on.
嘿，等等
Hey, wait a minute.
我先问你件事
Let me ask you something.
如果让一个人看
一本叫《魔鬼森林》的书，
If one was asked to read
a book caIIed ''DeviI Wood,''
这个人是不是可以认为
这书会是恐怖
one wouId be correct in assuming
that the book was scary
或者让人兴奋
或者有点恶搞，
or exciting or had
something ''deviIIy'' in it,
是不是？
wouIdn't one?
可以的
One wouId.
唔，那这人可就错了
WeII, then
one wouId be wrong.
怎么了，雷蒙德？
What's going on,
Raymond?
黛比拉想让我读这个，
这样我们就能有共同点了
Debra wants me to read this
so we have stuff in common.
可我对天发誓，
这破烂就像是马用镇静剂
But I swear to God, this sucker's
Iike a horse tranquiIizer.
这，听听这段。
听听第一行
Here, Iisten to this.
Listen to this first Iine.
“想象一场雨如此之美，
''Imagine a rain so beautifuI
它必定从不曾存在”
这是个什么意思？
it must never have existed.''
What does that mean?
这是什么意思？告诉我，快，
这是什么意思呀？
What does that mean? TeII me,
right now, what does that mean?
- 我不知道
- 是呀
- I don't know.
- Yeah.
因为这全是胡说八道。
你必须把这书合上
Because it's nonsense taIk.
You have to cIose this book.
是的，看来小雷米看不成比赛了
Yeah, Iooks Iike IittIe Raymie
can't watch the game.
他有家庭作业了
He's got homework.
这是另一件恶心、可怕的事
That's the other
stinking, horribIe thing.
她也想一起看比赛，
就像今天的尼克斯队
She wants to watch sports
together too, Iike the Knicks today.
为什么？
Why?
我们情人节一起看了比赛，
We watched the game together
on VaIentine's Day
显然进展不错――
and apparentIy that went weII--
粘在一起，瞎聊乱扯
the being together and taIking.
- 你们说的什么？
- 谁知道呢？
- What did you guys taIk about?
- Who knows?
所以我才叫你们过来
That's why I asked
you guys to come over.
我需要你们稍稍
分担一点她的注意力
I need you to kind of
absorb some of her.
那我们是你们
So we're Iike pawns
变态游戏里的卒子？
in your sick game?
如果她问起来，
If she asks,
Iet's just say that
就说你来是因为你还在为
you came by because you're
stiII bummed out
没有女朋友郁闷
about not having a girIfriend.
- 我就是还在为那个郁闷
- 好极了
- I am stiII bummed out about that.
- Perfect.
我回来了
I'm back.
好的，你不开心。
保持这个表情
Okay, you're not happy.
Keep that Iook.
- 嘿，买了点垃圾食品看比赛
- 啊，好主意
- Hey, got junk food for the game.
- Ah, sweet.
我把孩子放你妈那了，
这样咱们――
I dropped the kids off
at your mom's so we--
罗伯特来了？
Robert's here?
我知道。我知道
I know. I know.
本来应该是
咱们的“集体活动”时间
It's supposed to be
our ''do stuff together'' time.
我想他还在为
没女朋友的事郁闷，
And I think he's stiII depressed
about not having a girIfriend,
你知道，作为失败者
you know, being a Ioser.
还能怎么样呢？
What are you gonna do,
right?
又不能就那么把他踢出去
I can't just kick him out.
哦，唔，好吧
Oh, weII, okay.
是
Yeah.
- 这么说你在读这本书了？
- 是的
- So you're reading the book?
- Yeah.
是吗，你看着还喜欢吗？
Yeah, you Iiking it so far?
这实在非常、非常、
非常好
It's reaIIy very, very,
very, very nice.
那就好
Good.
- 嘿，罗伯特，你好吗？
- 还好
- Hey, Robert, how you doing?
- Okay.
- 只想过来走走
- 哦，好的，随时欢迎
- Just thought I'd stop by.
- Oh, good, anytime.
尼克斯又打起精神，
The Knicks are coming
back to Iife,
6粒不受阻截的投篮得分
now scoring six
unanswered buckets.
球现在在中场位置
Ward now with the baII
Ward的操控下……
at midcourt...
你这周的专栏写什么？
So what's your coIumn
about this week?
离中场休息还有45秒
45 seconds Ieft to go
in the haIf.
事实上，我正要写尼克斯队的比赛，
ActuaIIy, I'm doing it
about the Knicks,
所以咱们看着，这很好，是的
so it's good that
we're watching it, yeah.
有意思
Interesting.
你想挖挖我们的意见？
想谈谈吗？
WouId you Iike to bounce
some ideas off of us? TaIk about it?
嘿，爸，什么事？
Hey, Dad, what's up?
把薯片拿来。
就这个事
Pass me the chips.
That's what's up.
你来看比赛的，弗兰克？
Are you here
for the game, Frank?
不，来听妙语的
No, the sparkIing conversation.
好了，快点，屁股动起来！
Okay, come on,
move your ass!
嘿，爸――！
Hey, Dad--!
对不起――移动活跃点
Sorry-- step IiveIy.
这话不错
That's good.
拜托，接着，跳呀，跳起来！
Come on, get it,
jump, jump!
怎么了，她在等烤箱呢？
What, she waiting for something
to come out of the oven?
不，弗兰克，
No, Frank,
雷和我一起看篮球赛
Ray and I are watching
a basketbaII game together.
哦，他做什么了？
Oh, what did he do?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
他做错什么了，
你要这么对他？
What did he do wrong
that you'd do this to him?
别说了，爸
Stop it, Dad.
你知道，弗兰克，
你家也能收到比赛的
You know, Frank, the game is on
at your house, too.
嘿，别朝我发火。
雷请我来的
Hey, don't get mad at me.
Ray invited me.
骇人听闻的谎言
That's an outrageous Iie.
他也邀请你了？
He invite you, too?
我，呃……
I, uh...
对不起，雷蒙德，我试了
Sorry, Raymond, I tried.
放轻松
Easy now, easy.
- 我真不能相信你
- 好了，好的。让我……
- I cannot beIieve you.
- Okay, good. Let me--
- 真难以置信！
- 我只是――我只是――
- I cannot beIieve you!
- I just-- I just--
- 你只是什么？
- 你能不能让我把话说完？
- You just what?
- WiII you Iet me finish my sentence?
如果你让我说完，
那我就能说完
If you Iet me finish,
then I couId finish it.
唔，现在我不知道怎么说了。
这一切太突然了
WeII, now I'm at a Ioss for words.
This is aII so sudden.
真难以相信
你甚至不能和我一起看比赛，
I can't beIieve you can't even
watch sports with me,
你喜欢的事？
你非得拿他们俩当缓冲的？
something you Iike? You gotta have
these two over as buffers?
我不认为叫他们俩来
有什么大不了的
I didn't think inviting them over
wouId be such a big deaI.
他们很适合作伴
They're good company.
连我都不认这个帐
Even I don't buy that.
- 你有没有读一点那本书？
- 我读了很多了
- Have you read any of that book?
- I read a Iot.
- 是吗，讲的什么？
- 讲的是“一场雨那么美，
- Yeah, what's it about?
- About ''a rain that's so beautifuI,
我都不相信它存在”
I can't even beIieve
it existed.''
这是第一行。
你读了一行！
That's the first Iine.
You've read one Iine!
我正打算读第二行的，
And I was gonna read
the next one
我刚一从昏迷中苏醒
when I came out of my coma.
就这样？
So that's it?
你就没打算投入任何努力，
是不是？
You're just not gonna put
any effort into this, are you?
哦，别这样，我只是不认为
需要把咱们的生活
Oh, come on, I just don't think
we need to turn our Iives
上下颠倒，
就为了能有什么话题好谈
upside down just so we can have
more to taIk about.
尝试跟我说话会
“让你的生活上下颠倒”？
Trying to taIk to me is
''turning your Iife upside down''?
- 我只是――我――我――
- 别说了
- I just-- I-- I--
- Stop taIking.
是的，雷，别费事跟我说话了
Yeah, Ray, don't even
bother taIking to me.
享受你的昏迷吧
You just enjoy your coma.
好吧，也许我会的
AII right, maybe I wiII.
看，这就是为什么我不建立关系
See, this is why I stay
out of reIationships.
是的，是因为这个
Yeah, that's why.
哦，嗨，亲爱的。
你来接孩子？
Oh, hi, dear.
You here to pick up the kids?
哦，是的，是，孩子，
是的，一会就好，是的
Oh, right, yeah, the kids,
yeah, in a minute, yeah.
弗兰克说你和黛比拉
Frank said that you
and Debra were having
在进行大声的讨论
some sort
of a Ioud discussion?
别操心了，妈。
一切正常
Don't worry about it, Ma.
Everything's fine.
你在躲她？
You hiding from her?
是的
Yeah.
这可真是好事
Then this shouId be good.
你干什么，出门躲着？
What are you, hiding out?
不，我来接孩子。
我刚才不是问孩子了吗？
No, I'm picking up the kids.
Didn't I just ask for the kids?
- 搞什么，妈？
- 是啊，别麻烦了
- What the heII, Ma?
- Yeah, don't bother.
我来接他们
I'II get 'em.
我说了我接。
我又能力接他们
I said I'II get 'em.
I'm capabIe of getting them.
我说了我会接他们。
你们好吗，孩子们？
I said I wouId pick them up.
how you doing, kids?
我只是跟我父母大声招呼，哈？
I was saying heIIo
to my parents, huh?
人就不能跟自己所爱的人问个好？
A guy can't greet
his Ioved ones?
那你不介意跟他们呆在一起了？
So you don't mind
spending time with them?
哦，行了。
让我消停会行吗？
Oh, come on.
WiII you give me a break?
我试了，哈？
我没试吗？
I tried, huh? Didn't I try?
哦，好吧，我了解。
你生气我没跟你说话
Oh, okay, I get it. You're mad
at me for not taIking to you,
所以你现在不跟我说话了。
多有意思呀！
so now you're not taIking to me.
Isn't that interesting?
也许你应该考虑一下，哈？
Maybe you shouId think
about that, huh?
叼根烟斗就更帅了
Put that pipe
in your mouth, hmm?
什么？你看什么呢？
What?
What are you Iooking at?
需要帮忙吗？
May we heIp you?
- 不，我们没事
- 有只怪猫
- No, we're fine.
- There's a weird cat.
刚才在外头。
是的，现在走了
He was outside.
Yeah, it's gone now.
一只褐色的眼睛，
令一只好像没有眼睛
It had a brown eye
and, Iike, one no eye.
就是那样子。怪怪的
It was one of those.
It was weird.
- 喔
- 我知道。那真是……
- Wow.
- I know. That's reaIIy...
- 真的有点温馨
- 什么，那个？他们都没说话
- ReaIIy kind of sweet.
- What, that? They're not taIking.
唔，感觉他们不需要
WeII, it's Iike
they don't have to.
我不认为是他们不需要
I don't think it's 'cause
they don't have to.
我想是他们不想
I think it's 'cause
they don't want to.
我不知道
I don't know.
他们看起来那么合拍
They seemed so in tune.
我见到奶牛了
I see cows.
这有一只狗狗，
这还有一支狗狗
Here's one doggie,
and here's another doggie.
看看哪。好极了。
你知道吗？
Look at that. That's great.
You know what?
我需要你再画四只狗狗、
一只小鸡
I need you to draw up
four more doggies and a chicken.
你看好这个？
That Iooks good to you?
他们看起来和彼此那么舒服
They just seem so comfortabIe
with each other.
我不知道
I don't know.
也许咱们就要到达能够享受
Maybe we're at that point
where we can be comfortabIe
简单的彼此相处的那点上了
just being with each other.
你想像他们那样？
You wanna be Iike them?
也不完全是了
Not exactIy.
不过你想想，
如果咱们不那么操心
But just imagine how much better
our VaIentine's dinner
把每一秒钟都用奶油的话题填满，
wouId have been
if we weren't so worried
情人节晚餐会是多么好
about fiIIing up every singIe second
with taIk about butter.
是你唠叨个没完面包的事
You were the one
who was babbIing about the bread.
然后自然就会有我的奶油理论了
It's onIy naturaI you're gonna get
my butter theory.
好了，我知道。我知道，
AII right,
I know. I know,
可要是咱们能够简简单单地开心，
but what if we had
just been happy
就因为在外头，
to be out of the house,
就咱们俩，享受和平与安静呢？
just us enjoying
the peace and the quiet?
- 我的确喜欢安静
- 使得，我也是
- I do Iike quiet.
- Yeah, me, too.
还有和平
And peace.
我猜问题在于
I guess the question is
以后的30年里，
for the next 30 years,
在安静的时候，
when it's quiet,
而咱们也没什么要对彼此说的，
and we don't have anything
to say to each other,
我是不是介意你坐在我身边
do I mind having you
sit next to me?
不，我不介意
No, I don't mind.
哦，那就好
Okay, good.
- 你介意我做你身边吗？
- 不，你香香的
- You mind sitting next to me?
- No, you smeII good.
- 你为什么说30年？
- 哦，我不知道
- Why did you say 30 years?
- Oh, I don't know.
- 你认为我70岁的时候会死？
- 不
- Do you think I'm gonna die at 70?
- No.
- 因为30年是个奇怪的数
- 好了，嘘！
- 'Cause 30 years is a weird number.
- Okay, shh!
别说话了
Let's not taIk.
- 好的。对他们管用
- 是的
- Okay. It works for them.
- Yeah.
呃呵――我再也不能看他吃东西了
Ugh-- I can't Iook
at him eat anymore.
骑士队重整士气，
The CavaIiers came up
with a surprise upset,
108比99击败开拓者
beating the BIazers
108 to 99.
湖人轻易拿下火箭，
The Lakers had no troubIe
with the Rockets,
124比88
winning 1 24 to 88.
掘金以114比112险险击败尼克斯，
The Nuggets just got
by the Knicks 114 to 11 2.
超音速136比78击溃爵士
The Supersonics devastated
the Jazz 1 36 to 78.
开拓者98比94胜公牛
It was the TraiIbIazers
over the Bucks 98 to 94.
凯尔特奋战公牛，
110比108最终获胜
The CeItics edged
the BuIIs 110 to 108,
步行者121比113胜小牛
and the Pacers defeated
the Mavericks 1 21 to 11 3.
在维加斯，“勾拳手”Sammy Sterling
In Vegas, Sammy ''the Hook''
SterIing weighed in
体重212磅正
at 21 2 pounds even.
他比体重210正的“理发师”John Carter
He has a two-inch reach
over John ''the Barber'' Cutter,
高出两公分
who tipped the scaIes
at an even 210.
这场比赛将进行15回合
It's a scheduIed 15-rounder,
高尔夫球场上，
Palmer和Nicklaus在第三轮后并列排位第一……
and on the Iinks, PaImer and NickIaus
shared the third round Iead...
And are 11-under for the event.
英式足球中……
In soccer...
jojoba
yettoreturn@hotmail.com